We can see a similar process in the stock market.
股市也会出现类似的情况
If you find an Alpha signal that suggests that a stock will have positive future returns,
如果你发现某个 Alpha 信号可以告诉我们股票将在未来出现正收益
the assumption of future higher returns means that the price
未来收益更高这个假设
today is lower then the expected future price.
表明今天的股价比预期未来股价低
In other words, its current market price is cheap according to the signal.
也就是说 根据该信号 当前市场价格比较低
If you buy it now at this price,
如果现在以这个价格买入
and if your hypothesis was accurate,
并且你的假设是正确的
you'll be expecting the price to rise in the future.
那么未来股价会上涨
Now, what if lots of other investors also find
如果很多其他投资者也发现了同一信号
the same signal and also decide to buy the stock now?
并且也决定现在买入该股票 会怎样？
The buying activity will push the stock price higher.
买入行为将推动股价上涨
So, by the time you get around to buying yourself,
所以当你要买入时
the price has already risen.
股价已经上涨了
If you buy it like everyone else,
如果你像其他人一样买入
you may find that it doesn't produce the positive return you were hoping for.
可能会发现它并不能产生预期的正收益
This is an example of the efficient market hypothesis,
这就属于有效市场假说
which states that assets are fairly priced based on publicly available information.
该假设指出资产价格充分体现了公开信息
The factor is no longer helping to drive the mean return of our investments.
因子不再推动投资的均值收益
Instead, the factor is triggering the market price to move because
而是触发市场价格出现变化
it is known and being used for trade decisions by many other investors.
因为很多其他投资者知道该因子并根据它做出交易决策
So this factor is now driving the movement of the stock.
所以该因子现在会推动股票的变化
Every time the factor signal changes,
每次因子信号变化时
the market price also changes soon after.
市场价格很快也会变化
We now say that the factor is a risk factor.
现在我们说该因子是风险因子
So in summary, good Alpha factors enable us to find
总结下 好的 Alpha 因子
mispricings and seek a competitive edge in the market,
使我们能够发现错误定价 在市场中寻求竞争优势
which drives the mean return of a portfolio.
并推动投资组合的均值收益
When Alpha factors become two well-known,
当 Alpha 因子变得广为人知时
then they end up triggering the market to move as a changes,
就会触发市场也出现变化
which drives the variance of our portfolio's return,
它开始推动投资组合收益的方差
but no longer the mean of the return.
不再推动收益的均值
So now it's a risk factor.
所以现在是风险因子
Market participants historically have had to use their judgment and experience to decide
市场参与者以前需要根据经验判断
which factors to use as Alpha factors and which factors to use as risk factors.
将哪些因子作为 Alpha 因子 将哪些因子作为风险因子
Can we use AI to do this instead?
可以使用 AI 进行判断吗？
Yes we can. We'll go in depth into Alpha factor combination in term two.
可以我们将在第二学期深入讲解如何组合 Alpha 因子